J. Robert Oppenheimer Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- General Case File, 1799-1967 (Box 14-79)
  - Council on Atomic Implications, 1950-1962
  - Council on Higher Education in the American Republics
    - Lima, Peru, 1963-1965
    - Mexico, 1962-1963
  - Coral Gables conference, Coral Gables, Fla., 1964-1967, (2 folders) (Box 29)
  - Courant, Richard C., 1945-1954
  - Crytser, Robert and Glenda, 1961-1966
  - Cultural and Scientific Conference for World Peace, 1948-1949
  - Curtis, Charles P., 1954-1957
  - Cushman, Robert E., 1949
  - “D” miscellaneous, 1945-1967, (5 folders)
  - Dale, Ted, 1953-1966
  - Dancoff (Martha) Fund, 1952 (Box 30)
  - Dancoff, Sidney, 1949-1951
  - Daniel, Cuthbert, 1947-1949
  - Daniels, Farrington, 1950-1951
  - Dauer, Dorothea W., 1955 See also Container 76, Watanabe, Michael S.
  - Daughters, Charles, 1949
  - Davis, Robert, 1948-1954
  - Dean, Gordon
    - Correspondence, 1950-1966, (2 folders)
    - Speeches and lectures, 1949-1952
    - Statements
      - To commission, 1950
      - To press, 1950-1953
  - de Kauffmann, Henrik, 1949-1958
  - de Menasce, Jean P., 1951-1958
  - Democratic Advisory Committee, 1959
  - Dennes, William R., 1943-1962
  - Denver, University of, Denver, Colo., 1950-1951
  - de Rose, François
    - Auger notes, 1949-1966
    - Correspondence, 1947-1950
    - Parodi notes, 1949
    - Publications, undated
  - Deser, Stanley, 1955-1964
  - de Silva, Peer, 1944-1948
  - Deutsch, Monroe E., 1945-1955
  - DeWitt, Bryce Seligman, 1954-1967
  - Didesheim family, 1949
  - Dirac, Paul A. M., 1949-1965
  - Dodson, Richard, 1946-1951 (Box 31)
  - Dole, Vincent P., 1945-1957
  - Donzelot, Pierre, 1956-1957
  - Douglas, William O., 1962
  - Dow, David, 1945-1954
  - Dublin conference, Dublin, Ireland, 1965
  - DuBridge, Lee A.
    - Correspondence, 1945-1963
    - Speeches and articles, 1947-1953
  - Dulles, Allen Welsh, 1952-1953
  - DuMond, Jessie, 1948-1966
  - Durr, Clifford, 1948-1952
  - Dyshel, Benjamin H., 1956-1960
  - Dyson, Freeman, 1954-1966
  - “E” miscellaneous, 1942-1966, (2 folders)
  - Earle, Edward M., 1951-1963
  - Eastern Theoretical Physics Conference, 1962-1966, (2 folders)
  - Eaton, Cyrus S., 1957-1963
  - Echo Lake Symposium on Cosmic Rays, Echo Lake, Colo., 1949 (Box 32)
  - Edsall, John T., 1947-1966
  - Einstein, Albert (1879-1955), 1945-1959
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1949-1953
  - Eliot, George Fielding, 1947
  - Eliot, T. S., 1954-1956
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1954
  - Emergency Committee of Atomic Scientists, 1946-1949
  - Errera, Jacques, 1940-1963
  - European Organization for Nuclear Research See Container 26, CERN
  - Evans, Ward V., 1955-1956
  - “F” miscellaneous, 1945-1966, (4 folders)
  - Farrar, Clyde, 1948-1953 (Box 33)
  - Feer, Daniel B., 1949-1951
  - Feis, Herbert, 1952-1966
  - Feldman, David, 1950-1957
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1945-1951
  - Fergusson, Francis, 1947-1967
  - Fermi, Enrico, 1943-1952
  - Fermi Medal Fund, 1951-1963
  - Ferry group, 1964
  - Ferry meeting
    - Arrangements, 1963-1964
    - Documentation, 1963
  - Feynman, Richard P., 1946-1961
  - Fidler, H. A., 1948-1949
  - Field, Richard M., 1948-1959
  - Fieldston School, New York, N.Y., 1952
  - Finkelstein, Robert, 1955-1957
  - Finney, Nat, 1947-1950
  - Fischer, Louis, 1963-1966
  - Fisk, James, 1948
  - Fleming, H. K., 1951 (Box 34)
  - Flexner, Abraham, 1948-1957
  - Foldy, Leslie L., 1949-1964
  - Ford Foundation, 1948-1952
  - Fortune, 1945-1957
  - Frankfurter, Felix, 1947-1965
  - Frankfurter-Bohr papers, 1943-1962
  - Frederika, Queen, consort of Paul I, King of the Hellenes, 1960
  - Freistadt, Hans, 1949-1951
  - Frenkel-Brunswick, Elsa, 1952-1953
  - Frey, O., 1949-1951
  - Friedrich, W. G., 1957-1961
  - Friendly, Alfred, 1949
  - Friendly, Fred, 1963-1967
  - Fulton, John F., 1954-1959
  - Fund for the Republic, 1958
  - Furman, Robert R., 1943-1944
  - “G” miscellaneous, 1944-1967, (5 folders) (Box 35)
  - Galileo Conference, Italy, 1964
  - Galpin, Perrin, 1957-1966
  - Gamow, George, 1948-1956
  - Gandhi, Indira, 1966
  - Gardner, Trevor, undated
  - Gell-Mann, Murray, 1955-1965
  - George Washington University, Washington, D.C., 1947
  - Gilbert, Donald W., 1949 (Box 36)
  - Gilbert, G. M., 1948-1964
  - Gilpin, Robert, 1960-1964
  - Glauber, Roy J., 1952-1953
  - Glennan, T. Keith, 1951-1952
  - Goethe Bicentennial Foundation, 1949
  - Gold, Louis, 1950
  - Goldberger, Marvin L., 1954-1966
  - Golden, William T., 1951-1963
  - Goodridge, Edwin T., 1948-1953
  - Gottmann, Jean, 1954-1966
  - Gowing, Margaret, 1964-1965
  - Greece, visit, 1958
  - Grinfeld, Rafael, 1949-1963
  - Griswold, Alfred Whitney, 1959-1960
  - Groves, Leslie R., 1943-1967, (2 folders)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1948-1966
  - Gundlach, Ralph H., 1948-1951
  - Gurney, Ronald and Natalie, 1948-1958
  - "H" miscellaneous, 1943-1967, (6 folders) (Box 37)
  - Hadley, Arthur T., 1960-1961
  - Hafstad, Lawrence R.
    - Correspondence, 1949-1951
    - Speeches and articles, 1949-1950
  - Hamilton, Thomas I., 1950
  - Hammarskjöld, Dag, 1957-1961
  - Hammond, Paul, 1957-1961
  - Hancock, John M., 1946 (Box 38)
  - Hand, Learned, 1952-1955
  - Hanson, Norwood Russell, 1960-1963
  - Hardsog, Harry N., 1953-1959
  - Harrison, Wallace K., 1953-1959
  - Hartman, Robert S., 1955
  - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., 1949
  - Harwell Nuclear Physics Conference, Harwell, England, 1950
  - Hawkins, David, 1945-1963
  - Haynie, Robert A., 1948-1951
  - Heckscher, August, 1954-1967
  - Hegeman-Harris Co., 1961
  - Hempelmann, Eleanor and Louis, 1948-1961
  - Henderson, Frances, 1949-1966
  - Henderson, Malcolm C., 1948-1963
  - Henderson, Martha, 1957-1965
  - Henry, Barklie, 1950-1966
  - Hersch, Jeanne, 1965-1967
  - Heydenburg, Norman P., 1942-1943
  - Hickenlooper, Bourke B., 1948 (Box 39)
  - Hildebrand, Joel H., 1946-1949
  - Hirschfeld, Gerhard, 1949-1956
  - Hirschland, Bonnie, 1949-1960
  - Hirschland, Franz, Herbert, and Richard, 1947-1963
  - Hirschmann family abroad, 1948-1959
  - Hobson, Verna, 1967
  - Hochschild, Harold, 1954-1966
  - Hoffman, C. G., 1956-1960
  - Hogan, Charles A., 1948-1949
  - Holifield, Chet, 1955
  - Hollis, Everett L., 1949-1951
  - Holloway, Marshall G., 1942
  - Hong Kong, visit, 1960
  - Houtermans, Charlotte, 1951-1966
  - Hunt, John C., 1965-1967
  - Hutchins, Robert M., 1945-1963
  - Huxley, Julian, 1951-1964
  - Hyman, Harold T., 1953-1957
  - “I” miscellaneous, 1942-1967 (Box 40)
  - Industrial Research Institute, 1951-1952
  - Inglis, David R.
    - Correspondence, 1952-1953
    - Reports, 1952
  - Institute for International Order, 1958
  - Institute for Theoretical Physics, 1955
  - Institute of International Education, 1964
  - Instituto Venezolano de Investigaciones Cinetíficas, 1964-1966
  - International Atomic Energy Agency
    - Center for Training in Theoretical Physics, 1961-1966
    - Correspondence, 1960-1963
  - International Center for Generalization, Deauville, France, 1962-1963
  - International Conference, La Jolla, Calif., 1960-1961
  - International Conference on High Energy Physics, 1962-1966
  - International Symposium on Gravitational Collapse, 1963-1964
  - Isard, Walter, 1949
  - Israel, visit, 1958
    - General, 1958
    - Hebrew University, Jerusalem, Israel, 1958
    - Technion, 1958
    - Weizmann Institute of Science, Rehovoth, Israel, 1957-1958
  - “J” miscellaneous, 1946-1966, (2 folders) (Box 41)
  - Jacobson, David, 1953-1957
  - Japan, Committee for Intellectual Interchange
    - Clippings, 1960
    - Correspondence with Kasaka Takagi, 1959-1960
    - General, 1959-1961
    - Visit to Kiyokata Kusaka, 1960
  - Jastrow, Robert, 1953-1960
  - Jauch, J. M., 1949
  - Jefferson, Thomas (1743-1826), to William Munford, transcript of letter regarding science, 1799, 1943, 1948
  - Jessup, Philip C., 1954-1958
  - John Hay Whitney Foundation See Container 78, Whitney (John Hay) Foundation
  - Johnson, Albin E., 1948-1949
  - Johnson, Jesse C., 1949-1951
  - Johnson, Joseph E., 1951-1961
  - Johnson, Louise, 1947-1948 (Box 42)
  - Johnson, Thomas H., 1951-1952
  - Joliot-Curie, F.
    - Rutherford celebration, 1947-1952
    - Second World Peace Conference, 1950
  - Jones, Evan and Honora, undated
  - Josselson, Michael, 1963-1967
  - Jost, Res, 1957-1965
  - “Ka-Ki” miscellaneous, 1945-1966, (3 folders)
  - "Kj-Kz" miscellaneous, 1945-1966, (2 folders) (Box 43)
  - Kamen, Martin D., 1949
  - Kantorowicz, Ernst H., 1954-1963
  - Karplus, Robert, 1953-1963
  - Kaufmann, Robert D., 1955-1966
  - Kayser, Jacques and Jane, 1948-1966
  - Kearny, Cresson H., 1951
  - Kelder, Toon, 1952-1965
  - Kelly, Harry C., 1949
  - Kennan, George F.
    - Correspondence, 1949-1966
    - Foreign policy discussion group, 1950-1958
    - Press and publicity, 1952
    - Publications, 1950-1967
  - Kerney, James, 1951-1954
  - Keyes, Geoffrey, 1952-1953
  - Kidde, Walter, 1952-1954
  - Kingdon, K. H., 1947-1949
  - Kirkman, Robert W., 1947-1953
  - Kissinger, Henry, 1955-1962
  - Kistiakowsky, George, 1944-1963
  - Klock, Augustus, 1947-1963
  - Knapp, J. B., 1948-1949 (Box 44)
  - Knopf, Alfred, 1950-1961
  - Kostue, Doris, 1952-1954
  - Kowarski, Lew, 1948
  - Kramers, Hans, 1947-1952
  - Kraybill, H. L., 1948
  - Kroll, Norman, 1949
  - Kryter, Robert W., 1949
  - Kusaka, Shuichi, 1943-1948
  - “L” miscellaneous, 1943-1967, (6 folders)
  - La Jolla Conference See Container 40, International Conference, La Jolla, Calif. (Box 45)
  - Lamb, LaMar, 1950-1962
  - Landau, L., 1957-1961
  - Landshoff, Hans, 1950
  - Langmuir, David B., 1947-1950
  - Langmuir, Irving, 1948
  - Langsdorf, Walter, 1945-1966
  - Lansdale, John, 1943
  - LaPlante, Bryan, 1948-1953
  - Lapp, Ralph E., 1947-1948
  - Lauritsen, Charles C., 1945-1959
  - Lawrence, Ernest O., 1942-1947
  - Leake, Chauncey D., 1954-1966
  - Leary, Eleanor, 1947-1951
  - Leary, L. B., 1947-1948
  - LeBaron, Robert, 1949-1950
  - Lee, T. D. (Tsung Dao), 1953-1964
  - Lehman, Herbert H., 1961-1963
  - Leidesdorf, Samuel D., 1956-1967
  - Leray, Jean, 1954
  - Leva, Marx, 1952
  - Levy, David, 1950-1960
  - Lévy, Maurice, 1953-1963
  - Lewis, Harold W., 1948-1964
  - Lewis, Wilmarth S., 1954-1961
  - Libby, W. F., 1950-1951 (Box 46)
  - Library of Congress, Washington, D.C., 1950-1951
  - Life Magazine
    - Atomic bomb publicity, 1952
    - Reprints of articles, 1949-1957
  - Likely, Wadsworth, 1952
  - Lilienthal, David E.
    - Addresses as commissioner of the Atomic Energy Commission, 1947-1949, (3 folders)
    - Correspondence
      - From Oppenheimer, 1946-1950
      - To and from Oppenhe imer, 1946-1966
      - To Oppenheimer, 1947-1950
      - With others, 1949
    - Joint Congressional Committee on Atomic Energy, attack on Lilienthal, 1949
    - Publications, 1947-1953
    - Publicity, 1948-1949
  - Linowitz, Sol M., 1948-1963 (Box 47)
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1953-1957
  - Litton, Charles V., 1949
  - Llewellyn, F. B., 1951
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1948
  - Lomanitz, Rossi, 1943-1953
  - Longair, A. K.
    - Correspondence, 1949-1952
    - Press notices, 1949-1951
  - Look, 1950, 1963
  - Loomis, Wheeler, 1949-1954
  - Loughridge, Donald H., 1948-1949
  - Low, Francis, 1952-1963
  - Lowe, E. A., 1952-1963
  - Luedecke, Alvin R., 1949-1950
  - “Maa-Mar” miscellaneous, 1943-1967, (3 folders)
  - "Mas-Mor" miscellaneous, 1943-1967, (6 folders) (Box 48)
  - "Mos-My" miscellaneous, 1942-1966 (Box 49)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1949-1965
  - MacNeille, H. M., 1948
  - Manley, John H., correspndence
    - From Oppenheimer, 1942-1949
    - To and from Oppenheimer, 1942-1957
    - To members of the General Advisory Committee, Atomic Energy Commission, 1947-1950
    - To Oppenheimer, 1942-1955
    - To Tomei, Anthony A., 1948
  - Mansfield, Kenneth, 1951
  - Marks, Anne, 1962-1963
  - Marks, Herbert S., 1946-1960
  - Marmour, Milton, 1949
  - Marseilles, Walter W., 1949-1954
  - Marshak, Alfred E., 1947-1956
  - Marshak, Robert, 1948-1966
  - Martha Dancoff Fund See Container 30, Dancoff (Martha) Fund
  - Marvel, Josiah, 1951-1961
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Mass.
    - Center for the History of Science, 1957
    - Compton Seminar, 1962
    - Conference on Electrostatic and Higher Energy Accelerators, 1947- 1948
    - Study Committee for the Fine Arts, 1953
  - Mastik, Donald F., 1948-1954
  - May, Kenneth O., 1949-1955
  - McCleery, Robert, 1956-1963 (Box 50)
  - McCloy, John J., 1948-1963
  - McConnell, Robert A., 1947-1954
  - McCormack, James, 1947-1952
  - McFadden, Elizabeth, 1954-1963
  - McKibben, Dorothy, 1950-1964
  - McKibben, J. L., 1942
  - McMahon, Brien
    - Correspondence, 1948-1952
    - Oppenheimer letters to McMahon, 1949
    - Publications, 1949-1951
    - Publicity, 1950-1952
  - McMillan, Edwin M., 1943-1963
  - Mehta, G., 1955-1958
  - Mehta, Narend, 1957-1963
  - Menninger Foundation, Topeka, Kans., 1964
  - Menzel, Donald H., 1947-1949
  - Meyer, Agnes Elizabeth Ernst, 1954-1967 (Box 51)
  - Meyner, Helen and Robert, 1959-1960
  - Michel, Louis and Thérése, 1954-1966
  - Millis, Walter, 1952-1958
  - Mitchell, Allan, 1947-1957
  - Mitchell, Dana P., 1943-1950
  - Mitchell, Donna, 1951
  - Moe, Henry Allen, 1953-1955
  - Moehler, Nina, 1949-1960
  - Monnet, Jean, 1959
  - Morette, Cecile, 1950-1957
  - Morgenthau, Hans J., 1953-1956
  - Morison, Elting, 1959
  - Morrison, Orville C., 1950-1953
  - Morrison, Philip, 1943-1967
  - Morse, Philip M., 1947
  - Mrak, Emil, 1947-1963
  - Mumford, Lewis, 1950-1954
  - Mundt, Karl E., 1949
  - Muñoz Marín, Luis, 1965-1966
  - Murphree, Eger V., 1950-1952
  - Murrow, Edward R., 1946-1964
  - Mylk, Eugene, 1952
  - “N” miscellaneous, 1945-1967, (3 folders) (Box 52)
  - Nabokov, Nicolas, 1961-1967
  - Nambu, Yoichiro, 1954-1963
  - Nathan, Otto, 1956-1961
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1956-1961
  - National Arts Foundation, 1948-1955
  - National Council for Social Studies, 1950
  - National Education Association, 1948-1958
  - National Industrial Conference Board, 1949-1952
  - National Planning Association, 1952
  - National Science Foundation
    - House and Senate, 1946-1953
    - Miscellany, 1947-1962
  - Nehru, Jawaharlal, 1949-1964
  - Nekrassoff, V. A., 1955
  - Nelson, Otto L., 1951
  - Neugebauer, Otto, 1954-1966
  - Neumann, Honora, 1956-1966
  - Newman, James R., 1949-1956 (Box 53)
  - New Republic
    - Articles sent to Oppenheimer, 1951
    - Correspondence, 1964
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1946-1950
  - New York Times, 1950-1958
  - Nishina, Yoshio, 1950
  - Nitze, Paul H., 1954-1955
  - Nobel Prize, 1952-1956
  - Noel-Baker, Philip, 1955-1958
  - Norman, Dorothy, 1952
  - North Carolina, University of, Chapel Hill, N.C., 1955-1957
  - Norton, Henry K., 1953-1954
  - Nucleonics, 1947-1948
  - “O” miscellaneous, 1943-1967, (2 folders)
  - O'Brian, John Lord, 1954-1963
  - Oliphant, Mark L., 1941-1963
  - On Film, Inc., 1961
  - Organization of American States, visiting professorship (Box 54)
    - Argentina
      - General, 1960-1961
      - Press, 1961
    - Brazil
      - General, 1961-1962
      - Press, 1961
    - Chile, 1962-1963
    - Correspondence, 1960-1963
    - General, 1961
    - Mexico, 1961
    - Uruguay, 1961
  - Osborn, Frederick
    - Correspondence, 1947-1958, (2 folders)
    - Publications, 1947-1950
    - United Nations statements, 1947-1949
  - Osmond, Humphry, 1952-1956
  - “P” miscellaneous, 1945-1967, (5 folders) (Box 55)
  - Page, Katherine, 1946-1950
  - Pais, Abraham, 1947-1966
  - Panofsky, Erwin, 1954-1966
  - Paris, University of, Paris, France, visiting professor, 1958 (Box 56)
    - General, 1951-1958
    - Le Monde interview, 1958
    - Press, 1958
  - Parker, David B., 1948
  - Parks, G. B., 1951
  - Parsons, William S., 1944-1952
  - Parvin Foundation
    - Chile trip, 1961-1962
    - Ecuador trip, 1955-1962
    - Miscellany, 1961-1963
    - Peru trip, 1962
  - Patterson, Robert P., 1946
  - Pauli, Herta, 1949
  - Pauli, Wolfgang, 1943-1949
  - Pauling, Linus, 1954-1964
  - Peierls, R. E., 1942-1965 (Box 57)
  - Penrose, Ernest F., 1953-1957
  - Perkins, James A., 1951-1953
  - Perpessa, Harilaas, 1950-1958
  - Peters, Bernard, 1944-1959
  - Petersen, Ignatius, 1955-1958
  - Physical Review, 1948-1955
  - Physics Today, 1948-1967
  - Pickett, Clarence, 1958-1959
  - Pike, Sumner T.
    - Correspondence, 1945-1951
    - Publications, talks, 1947-1951
  - Pines, David, 1948-1966
  - Pitzer, Kenneth S.
    - Correspondence, 1945-1951
    - General Advisory Committee, Atomic Energy Commission, 1952-1962
  - Placzek, George, 1949-1964
  - Pocono Manor Inn, 1949
  - Pope John XXIII, “Pacem in Terris,” 1963
  - Powell, C. F., 1948-1950
  - President's Committee on Scientists and Engineers, 1947-1958
  - President's Committee on the National Medal of Science, 1964 (Box 58)
  - Price, Derek, 1959-1963
  - Princeton Association of Scientists, 1948
  - Princeton Conference on the Goals of Scholarship in the Classics, 1949
  - Princeton Group for the Study of Defense Problems, 1957-1958
  - Princeton Seminars in Literary Criticism, 1950-1952
  - Princeton University, Princeton, N.J.
    - Conference on Satellites and Diplomacy, 1957-1958
    - Correspondence, 1956-1966
    - Nuclear Interaction Conference, 1950
  - Procopov, Constantine, 1950
  - Public Affairs Pamphlets (publisher), 1955-1960
  - Puerto Rico, higher education and advanced study, 1967
  - Puerto Rico, University of, Río Piedras, P.R., 1960
  - Pugwash Conference, Kitzbühel, Austria, 1949-1965 (Box 59)
  - Purcell, Edward M., 1953
  - Pyramid Club, 1959
  - “Q” miscellaneous, 1946-1965
  - Quantum physics, history of, 1962-1963
  - “R” miscellaneous, 1943-1967, (6 folders)
  - Rabi, I. I.
    - Correspondence, 1942-1962
    - Publications, 1949-1950
  - Rabinowitch, Eugene, 1957-1962 (Box 60)
  - Radin, Max, 1948-1951
  - Ramsey, Norman, 1945-1963
  - Raskin, Marc G., 1961
  - Raymond, Natalie, 1947-1949
  - Reader's Digest, 1945-1964
  - Réalités, 1957-1963
  - Reddy, Mary I., 1955-1956
  - Reese, C. Robert, 1950-1955
  - Reporter, 1949-1954
  - Reston, James, 1956
  - Reuther, Walter (1907-1970), 1950
  - Reynolds Metals Co., 1948
  - Richtmyer, Robert D., 1947
  - Ridenour, Louis N., 1943-1952
  - Ringuet, L. LePrince, 1949-1966
  - Roberg, Jane, 1944-1950
  - Robertson, Kenneth D., 1952-1954
  - Rochester High Energy Nuclear Physics Conference, Rochester, N.Y.
    - Third conference, 1952-1953
    - Fourth conference, 1953-1954
    - Fifth conference, 1954-1955
    - Sixth conference, 1955-1956 (Box 61)
    - Seventh conference, 1956-1957
    - Eighth conference, CERN, 1958
    - Ninth conference, Kiev, 1958-1959
    - Tenth conference
      - General, 1959-1960
      - Planning committee, 1960
      - Session S-2, 1960-1962
    - Eleventh conference, 1961-1963 (Box 62)
  - Rochester conference, Rochester, N.Y., 1963-1964
  - Rochester, University of, Conference on Meson Physics, Rochester, N.Y., 1951-1953
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1952
  - Roe, Ann, 1949
  - Rohrlich, Fritz, 1950-1965
  - Romains, Jules, 1955-1960
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor (1884-1962), 1950-1965
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D. (1882-1945), 1943
  - Rosenberg, Ethel and Julius, 1952-1966
  - Rosenwald, Lessing J., 1954-1966
  - Rossi, Bruno, 1947-1965
  - Rottnem, Mrs. Ralph, 1957
  - Rowe, A. P., 1949
  - Rowe, Hartley, 1945-1949
  - Rubin, Morris and Mary, 1947-1953
  - Russell, Bertrand, 1962-1963
  - Russell, Francis H., 1946-1949
  - Russell, Katherine, 1947-1962
  - Russia, 1949, 1963
  - Rutherford Memorial, 1950
  - Ryder, Arthur
  - “Sa-Sm” miscellaneous, 1942-1967, (8 folders) (Box 63)
  - "Sn-Sz" miscellaneous, 1945-1967, (5 folders) (Box 64)
  - Saavedra, Igor, 1963
  - Sachs, Alexander, 1946-1963
  - Sachs, Robert, 1945-1964
  - Salam, Abdus, 1960-1965
  - Salisbury, Morse, 1948-1950
  - Salk, Jonas, 1958-1962
  - Salmamé, Mario, 1965
  - Salpeter, E., 1952-1966
  - Samuels, Gertrude, 1954-1957
  - Sandri, Guido, 1963-1964
  - San Francisco Museum of Art, San Francisco, Calif., 1943-1946
  - Santos, Enid, undated
  - Saturday Review, 1956-1958
  - Schafroth, Max Robert, 1949-1957 (Box 65)
  - Schary, Dore, 1954-1959
  - Schein, Marcel, 1947-1954
  - Schiff, Leonard I., 1946-1963
  - Schilling, Warner R., 1956-1957
  - Schimmel, Herbert, 1948-1963
  - Schlesinger, Arthur M. (1917-2007) 1962-1966
  - Schoenberg, Mario, 1948
  - Schrecker, Paul, See Container 15, Anshen, Ruth Nanda
  - Schweitzer, Albert, 1955
  - Schwinger, Julian, 1963
  - Scientific American, correspondence
    - Piel, Gerard, 1948-1956
    - Svirsky, Leon, 1949
  - Scientists Committee on Loyalty Problems, 1948-1949
  - Scurlock, J. C., 1948-1949
  - Seaborg, Glenn T., 1942-1951
  - Seattle International Congress on Theoretical Physics, Seattle, Wash. (Box 66)
    - General, 1955-1957
    - Panel on quantum electronics, 1955-1956
  - Segrè, Emilio, 1944-1964
  - Seitz, Frederick, 1948-1966
  - Seligman, Bryce, 1950-1954
  - Serber, Charlotte and Robert, 1942-1965
  - Seven Springs Farm, Mt. Kisco, N.Y.
    - Establishment, 1961-1963
    - General, 1963-1966
    - Meetings, 1962-1967, (6 folders)
  - Shapiro, Irving, 1955 (Box 67)
  - Shugg, Carleton, 1948-1951
  - Sigma Pi Sigma, 1947-1949
  - Skinner, Herbert, 1947-1950
  - Slotin, Louis, 1946-1966
  - Slowen, Jessie A., 1951-1952
  - Smith, Carleton, 1959-1966
  - Smith, Alice and Cyrill S., 1948-1963
  - Smith, Herbert W., 1945-1956
  - Smyth, Henry DeWolf
    - Correspondence, 1946-1953
    - Speeches, 1949-1950
  - Snapp, Roy B., 1947-1952
  - Snyder, Hartland, 1947-1949
  - Sobell, Helen, 1956-1967
  - Society for Social Responsibility in Science, 1950
  - Solvay Congress (Box 68)
    - 1951-1952, 1961, (3 folders)
    - 1964
      - Arrangements
      - Correspondence
      - Scientific committees
    - 1967
  - Spaceboard Game Co. See Container 28, Cornish, Edward and Robert (Box 69)
  - Spears, Mary, 1954-1955
  - Speisman, Gerald, 1956-1959
  - Spencer, Floyd, 1953-1954
  - Spender, Stephen, 1956-1965
  - Spitzer, Lyman, 1951
  - Sporn, Philip, 1951-1954
  - Sproul, Kathleen, 1955-1963
  - Sproul, Robert G., 1943-1946
  - Stanford University, Stanford, Calif.
    - Correspondence, 1957-1963
    - Oppenheimer visit, 1964
  - State Department, 1952
  - Steinacher, Hermann, 1957
  - Steinberger, Jack, 1948-1963
  - Stern, Alexander, 1949-1964
  - Stern, Hedwig, 1944-1966
  - Stern, Hilde, 1948-1966
  - Stern, Walter, 1952-1963
  - Stern family abroad, 1948-1958
  - Stevens, Herbert H., 1950-1952
  - Stevenson, Adlai E. (1900-1965)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1966
    - Publications, publicity, 1956
  - Stewart, Stanley, 1943-1955 (Box 70)
  - Stone, Marshall H., 1953-1963
  - Stone, Shepard, 1954-1963
  - Strauss, Lewis L.
    - Correspondence, 1947-1963
    - Publications, talks, 1948-1949
  - Streit, Clarence, 1947-1954
  - Strunsky, Robert, 1950-1955
  - Sugiura, Yashikatsu, 1947-1961
  - Suits, Guy, 1945-1954
  - The Symposium, 1955-1956
  - Szilard, Leo, 1945-1963
  - “T” miscellaneous, 1945-1966, (5 folders) (Box 71)
  - Taketani, Mituo, 1948-1949
  - Tata Institute Conference on Elementary Particles, Bombay, India, 1950
  - Taylor, Harold, 1954-1964
  - Taylor, John G., 1959-1965
  - Taylor, Telford, 1958-1963
  - Teeter, John H., 1945-1952
  - Teller, Edward, 1942-1963
  - Theoretical Physics Conference (Box 72)
    - 1947, Shelter Island
    - 1948, Poconos
    - 1949, Oldstone
      - Correspondence, 1945-1949
      - Notes, 1949
  - Thirring, Walter, 1955-1961
  - Thomas, Charles Allen, 1944-1949
  - Thomas, Norman, 1959-1964
  - Thompson, Homer, 1954-1958
  - Time, Inc., encyclopedia project, 1962-1963
  - Time Magazine, 1950-1952
  - Tingsten, Herbert, 1954
  - Tolman, Edward C., 1953-1959
  - Tolman, Ruth, 1943-1958
  - Tomei, Anthony A. (Box 73)
    - Correspondence
      - Dodson, Richard, 1951
      - Manley, John H., 1949-1951